Finding Aid for John T. Kelsey Papers 1969-1982
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John T. Kelsey Papers 1969-1982
Kelsey, John T., 1921-
2 oversized volumes
2 linear feet
Democratic State Representative from Warren, Michigan. Subject files, newsletters, constituent responses, and scrapbooks of clippings and correspondence; include material concerning the use of laetrile, cross district busing, the problems of the aged, and other legislative issues of the 1970s.
85240 Aa 2 AC
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mr. Kelsey (donor no. 6861 ) in December 1982-January 1983.
The collection is open for research.
John T. Kelsey was born in Detroit, Michigan, on December 22, 1921. He attended Detroit school and the Detroit College of Law from 1960 to 1961.
Kelsey was a journeyman tool maker and real estate salesman, and served in the US Army from 1942 to 1945. His public service career began in 1951 when he was elected as a township trustee. He was also Justice of the Peace for Warren Township, 1953-1958; Municipal Judge of the City of Warren, 1958-1961; and a delegate to the Constitutional Convention, 1961-1962. He was elected to the State House of Representatives in 1964, and to each succeeding session until his retirement in 1982. Kelsey represented the 70th District, comprising Macomb County, the city of Center Line, and part of the City of Warren.
The Kelsey papers consist of two feet of legislative papers, 1971-1982. Included are subject files, newsletters, constituent responses, and scrapbooks of clippings and correspondence. Topics in the collection concern the use of laetrile, cross district busing, the problems of the aged, and other legislative issues of the 1970s.
Subjects:
Busing for school integration--Michigan.; Democratic Party (U.S.); Kelsey, John T., 1921-; Laetrile.; Legislators--Michigan.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Old age.; Warren (Mich.)
Genre/Form:
Scrapbooks.
- Biographical Material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Issue Files
  Issues consist of correspondence and other collected materials on issues of interest to Kelsey. Some of the files concern school busing, laetrile, and problems of the aged. These files have been arranged alphabetically.
  - Age of Majority 1971-1975 (Box 1)
  - Busing
    - Clippings 1975-1976, 1979, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1972 (Box 1)
      - 1976 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Materials 1971-1974 (Box 1)
  - Committee Assignments 1974 (Box 1)
  - Educational Parks 1971 (Box 1)
  - Finance and Taxation 1973 (Box 1)
    correspondence with office of Florida Governor Reubin Askew
  - Laetrile 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - Legal Decisions, Opinions, and Orders
    - Attorney General
      - 1959-1968 (Box 1)
      - 1969-1974 (Box 1)
      - 1975-1978 (Box 1)
      - Striking Workers 1970 (Box 1)
      - Open Meetings Act 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Supreme Court
      - Financing Public School Education 1972 (Box 1)
      - Legislative Apportionment 1972 (Box 1)
      - No-Fault Automobile Insurance 1973 (Box 1)
      - Motor Vehicle Gasoline Tax 1974 (Box 1)
      - Jackie Vaughn 1974 (Box 1)
      - Constitutionality of Acts 240 and 301, Public Acts of 1976 (Box 1)
    - United States Supreme Court
      - Abortion 1973 (Box 1)
  - Loch Erin, Inc. (Grace Clark) 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - News Releases 1969-1982 (Box 1)
  - No-Fault Auto Insurance
    - 1972 (Box 1)
    - 1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1)
  - Political Reform Act 1975
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 1)
  - POW's and MIA's (Susan Sembec) 1974 (Box 1)
  - Regional Planning 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - Resolutions 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Social Security and Welfare 1971-1973 (Box 2)
  - Thank you Letters
    - 1969-1972 (Box 2)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - 1979 (Box 2)
  - Unicameral Legislature 1971 (Box 2)
- Mailings (largely newsletters)
  The Mailings series consist largely of newsletters distributed by Kelsey, and constituent responses to these mailings. These files have been arranged chronologically.
  - 1969 (Box 2)
  - 1970 (Box 2)
  - 1971 (Box 2)
  - 1972
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1973
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1974
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1975
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
    - Re Detroit Metro Water Board (Box 2)
    - Re Public Service Commissioners (Box 2)
    - Re Social Security (Box 2)
  - 1976
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
    - Re: Banning use of toxic or dangerous chemicals (Box 2)
  - 1977
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1978
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1979
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1980
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1981
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
  - 1982
    - Newsletters (Box 2)
    - Responses (Box 2)
- Personal
  - Notebook containing letters received upon his retirement from the state House of Representatives 1982 (Box 2)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook containing copies of clippings and correspondence re debate over use of laetrile 1977-1979 (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook containing clippings and correspondence re political career 1966-1982 (Volume 2)